## Dhruvyasha Patel

## Fashion Designer/Business Developer and Retail Management

Current: Sudbury, ON T: +1(236) 989 5888 E:patel.dhruvyasha@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Accomplished design/business professional with over 4 years of performance in the fashion/retail industry. Portfolio of achievements includes increase in yearly/monthly sales, driving profit and improving customer services. Broad-based background encompasses exceptional work ethic and commitment to organizational objectives. Sales manager, team builder and tactical planner with ability to train and motive top performance. Contributed to company's growth leading sales and businesses through a combination of creativity, initiative and strong leadership.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# ROCK ARCHER LEATHER Ltd. | Toronto, ON Technical Apparel Designer (Remote, PT)

January 2023 – Present

- Design technical spec sheet of men's jackets.
- Collection of men's Leather Jackets
- Design apparel for upcoming retail brand.
- Other duties as directed by the company.

#### ARDENE | Sudbury, ON

Retail Sales Supervisor/Third Key Holder (FT)

**June 2022- February 2023** 

- Perform and supervise store opening and closing procedures including counting register funds, completing bank deposits, and securing facility.
- Assisting the Store Manager in the achievement of the company objectives and KPI goals.
- Understanding of sales principle and customer service practices.
- Identify and resolve problems in a timely manner. Use feedback to modify and develop alternative solutions and be prepared to make decisions.
- Leading and mentoring team of 7-9 team members.
- Receiving and sorting the shipment every week. Stocking of new merchandise according to the company policies.
- Collaborate with Store Manager in areas of risk management, physical security (health & safety), store cash controls (bank deposits, safe funds, petty cash), and inventory management (stock take, stock counts)
- Follow up of all the new signage for all new promotions.
- Processing and shipping of OMNI-channel orders.
- Designing and creating visual displays of windows, walls, and podiums according to the company monthly launch pack.
- Performing all other duties as directed by the Store Manager.

#### THE COLORS OF NATURE | Auroville, India

The colors of nature have revived 100% natural indigo dyeing process in its eco-friendly fashion products.

#### Jr. Fashion Designer

January 2018 - June 2018

Sustainable Women's and Men's wear design collection

- Pattern making, Sampling
- Sales Assistant: Provide exceptional customer service to prospective customers.
- Product Styling guide for the customers

#### **Brand Inventory Manager** (FT)

February 2021 – February 2022

• Track all the product information

- Maintenance of the stock in the warehouse
- Receiving and stocking shipment in the store.
- Follow up of all the changing price points.
- Recording daily products and upcoming shipments.

#### **Quality Control Analyst (FT)**

February 2021 – February 2022

- Quality Control Analyst for "STORY MFG" London based fashion company
- Ensure product's meet the required standard measurements and quality
- Recommendations on how to repair defects
- Inspection to ensure products meet best standards according to the company's spec sheet.

#### EQUIIVALENCE | Ahmedabad, India

Urbane Sustainable Fashion and Jewelry brand

#### **Fashion Designer and Business Strategist**

May 2020 - December 2020

Designing new collections for Equivalence brand (Shirt and Tie collection)

- Sourcing Thrift stores and second handed clothes for Jewelry photoshoot.
- Preparing Circular designs & strategies for the company
- Fabric sampling and Designing Zero Waste patterns technique.

#### MC DONALD'S | Hanwell, London

Part time/Full time employment in London while pursuing higher education in London University

Crew Member February 2019 – July 2019 Floor Manager August 2019 – March 2020

- Supervising and operating day-to-day functions
- Training new employees and staff
- Handling customer complaint and offering best service

#### SHIVALIK PRINT LTD | Haryana, India

A world class resource for fabric knitting, processing, finishing and garment manufacturing.

### **Assistant Fashion Designer**

May 2017 – July 2017 (3 Months Internship)

- Organize fabric warehouse
- Technical knowledge of Knitted Fabrics
- Research seasonal trends.
- Other duties as assigned by the Designer

**Key achievement**: Designed embroidery designs and patterns for JC Penny women's wear collection.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Post-Graduation Diploma in Fashion Business Creation

• Business strategy and brand management.

• Fashion branding and marketing.

Research skills and communication methods.

Understanding Sustainability concept in the Fashion Industry

#### **BA Design in Fashion Design**

• Pattern Making / Creative Pattern Making

Prototype development

Fashion Illustrations / Illustrations

• Fashion styling | Fashion Photography

January 2019 – May 2021

Glasgow Caledonian University

London, United Kingdom

July 2014 - July 2018 Karnavati University

Unitedworld Institute of design

Gujarat, India

#### **EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### GCU London | The Common Good Fashion Show:

- Charity fashion show
- Lead a team of 4 members for fashion walk.
- Styling attire according to the theme.

#### GCU London | British Beauty Council

- Debate with the CEO of British Beauty Council
- Assisted for British Beauty Council Members for the event

#### **Guest Speaker | Slow Fashion Movement**

- Sharing knowledge on finding personal style in a sustainable way.
- Engage and communicate with the community and ambassadors

#### ONLINE CERTIFICATE AND SHORT COURSES

- Fashion and sustainable: Understanding luxury fashion in a changing world | London college of fashion and Kering
- Fashion's future: The sustainable development goals | Fashion Revolution
- Sustainable Fashion: Copenhagen Business School
- Fashion Technology: A beginner's guide to CLO 3D: University for the Creative Arts

#### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Microsoft office
- Adobe Creative Cloud- Illustrator
- CLO 3D Design Software
- Leadership skills
- Communication skills
- Teamwork and Team management
- Working in fast paced environment
- Planning and Organizing
- Project Management
- Retail Management
- Customer Service